

# Zachary Branson

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

**Phone:** (936) 676-5542

Address: 12106 Jamie Dr. Manor Tx, 78653

**Email:** zac21261@gmail.com **Website:** zacharybranson.com

**GitHub:** https://github.com/zac1127

## **PROFILE**

I am 25 years old, and currently a Senior Software Developer at Mattersight. I have been married to my wife Danica, and we recently had our first child Emma. I am a hard-working, detailed programmer, looking for new opportunities to use my skills and expand my knowledge as a software engineer.

Making Responsive, and interactive websites has been a passion of mine since a very young age. Every new web application I make, my goal is to make sure it is better than the last. I would love the opportunity to speak further about the open position, to know if the skills I have can benefit your organization.

Thank you for taking the time to consider me for the open position.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **Mattersight**

Apr 2018 - Present

#### Senior Software Developer

I currently work on a team with goals to improve and maintain a large-scale web application. I had the opportunity to work on major projects that improved the functionality and performance of the product. I worked as a full stack developer, with responsibilities that scaled from frontend to backend, and database management.

# **Mattersight**

#### Software Developer

Jun 2017 - Apr 2018

I currently work on a team with goals to improve and maintain a large-scale web application. I had the opportunity to work on major projects that improved the functionality and performance of the product. I worked as a full stack developer, with responsibilities that scaled from frontend to backend, and database management.

# **Elevation Church**

Feb 2017 - Jun 2017

#### Web Application Developer (contract position)

Built and maintained a social media like mobile application for staff to track fitness, nutrition, and bible studies. Users have the ability post achievements, add profile pictures, and comment on posts. I built using the Laravel PHP framework with a MySQL backend. I used HTML, CSS, and JOuery for the front-end development.



### **Web Developer**

## **Software Developer**

### **Other**

- HTML
- PHP
- Java
- OOP
- **Jenkins**

- CSS
- Laravel
- Visual Basic Git

- JavaScript MySQL
- C++

Postman

- JQuery
- SOL Server

Redis

## **EDUCATION**



- Stephen F. Austin State University, Nacogdoches, Texas
- ABET (Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology) Accredited University, <a href="http://www.abet.org/">http://www.abet.org/</a>
- Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

## **REFERENCES**

# Luke **Clement**

(501) 773-8100

#### **Software Engineer at Dropoff**

Dropoff is a same-day pickup and delivery service that enables businesses across industries to meet rising expectations for faster deliveries.



(936) 414-6534

M&A advisor at Fleet Ridge Pacific

Fleet Ridge Pacific is a company that handles critical issues surrounding mergers and acquisitions in the healthcare industry.